Alfred H. Nolle papers 90.200.Faculty.1980.Nolle
University Archives, Texas State University
- Miscellaneous publications, 1881-1978; 1.50 Linear Feet
  Alfred H. Nolle collected a number of publications related to his interests in education administration and German language education and his admiration of Southwest Texas State Teachers College alum Lyndon B. Johnson. Included in this series are publications related to teacher education, German language, education of Latin-American students, and Lyndon B. Johnson. Publications related to the history of Southwest Texas State Teachers College and works about and by students, faculty, and staff are also included. Items date from 1881 through 1978.
  - Geschichten aus Kirche und Welt zu M. Luthers kleinem Katechismus: Für Kirche, Schule und Haus, Hermann Fick, 1881 (Volume BX8070.L8 G47 1881)
  - Deutsches Kommersbuch, Karl Reissert, 1896 (Volume M1961 .R483 1896)
  - Bulletin of the First District Normal School, Kirksville, Missouri, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - University of Pennsylvania Graduate School catalog, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Athenais: Trauerspiel in Fünf Akten, Heinrich Sibberns, 1922 (Volume PT2639.I14 A7 1922)
  - "The Problem of Foreign Languages in the School and College Curriculum," Henry Dexter Learned, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Student's Hand-book of the Southwest Texas State Normal College, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Student's Hand-book of the Southwest Texas State Teachers College, 1923, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Student's Hand-book of the Southwest Texas State Teachers College, 1928-1933 (Box 10)
  - Arnold Merten's Modell, Anna Fink, 1930 (Volume PT3919.F49 A7 1930)
  - Rheinsagen, A. Kenngott, 1931 (Volume PF3127.F3 K4 1931)
  - Demonstration School Demonstrator, vol. 1 no. 11, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Getting and Communicating Thought, Gates Thomas, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Das Buch von Deutschen Volkstum: Wesen, Lebensraum, Schicksal, Paul Gauss, 1935 (Volume DD61 .B83 1935)
  - Neutestamentliches Wörterbuch: Eine Einführung in Sprache und Sinn des Urchristlichen Schrifttums, Ralf Luther, 1937 (Volume BS2312 .L87 1937)
  - Bulletins on Latin-American child education, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "Alabama and the Texas Revolution," Claude Elliot, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - A College Looks at Its Program, Southwest Texas State Teachers College, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Fifty Years of Teacher Education, Joe B. Vogel, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - National Conservation Training Program for the United States of America, Arthur A. Grusendorf, circa 1951 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - "The Exploding World of Education," Nathan M. Pusey, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Sewanee Alumni News, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - A College Re-Examines Its Program, Southwest Texas State Teachers College, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Congressional Record, 86th Congress First Session, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Emphasis Upon Excellence, William F. Brown, et al., 1964 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "L. B. J. Country," Bill Porterfield, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Johnson Humor, Lyndon B. Johnson, 1965 (Volume E847 .A25 1965 c.2)
  - LBJ Country, Bill Porterfield, 1965 (Volume F391.2 .P6 1965 c.4)
  - Lyndon Baines Johnson: The Formative Years, William C. Pool, 1965 (Volume E847 .P6 1965 c.5)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson: The Exercise of Power, Rowland Evans, 1966 (Volume E847 .E9 1966 c.4)
  - The Administration of John Garland Flowers: Third President of Southwest Texas State College by Tommy Ruth Ball, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Life, Special Issue The Presidency, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Limestone and Log: A Hill Country Sketchbook, J. Roy White, 1968 (Volume F387 .W57 1968 c.5)
  - To Heal and to Build: The Programs of Lyndon B. Johnson, Lyndon B. Johnson, 1968 (Volume J82 .E1 1968 c.6)
  - Life, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Persona, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Memorial Services in the Congress of the United States and Tributes in Eulogy of Lyndon Baines Johnson, Late a President of the United States, United States Congress, 1973 (Volume E847 .U57 1973 c.4)
  - NOVA (University Star supplement), 1978 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Newspapers papers and clippings, 1921-1977, undated; 0.33 Linear Feet
  Clippings are arranged by subject and then chronologically.
  Dr. Nolle collected newspapers and newspaper clippings related to Southwest Texas State University, Lyndon B. Johnson, and his career and personal life. Clippings related to Dr. Nolle include announcements related to his speaking engagements, Alpha Chi events, and his receipt of awards. University events are also included as well as faculty and student awards and recognition and articles related to past University presidents. Clippings also document Lyndon B. Johnson's political career, his relationship and visits to SWTSTC, his retirement, and his wife, Lady Bird Johnson.
  - Newspaper clippings, Lyndon B. Johnson, 1950-1965, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings, Lyndon B. Johnson, 1966-1971 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper clippings, Lyndon B. Johnson, 1971-1977 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clippings, Alfred H. Nolle, 1921-1935 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper clippings, Alfred H. Nolle, 1936-1949 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper clippings, Alfred H. Nolle, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, Alfred H. Nolle, 1960-1977 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1928-1944 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, University, 1955-1978 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Newspapers, 1928-1973 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Separated to Student newspaper collection.
- Photographs, before 1919-1970, undated; 0.02 Linear Feet; 14 items
  Photographs are arranged chronologically
  This series includes 14 photographs dating from before 1919 through 1970. Five photographs are Nolle portraits. The date of creation for two of these photographs is estimated to be before 1919 as the photographer's imprint indicates the photograph was taken in Columbia, Missouri. Hence, these photographs were probably taken when Nolle was in graduate school or teaching at the University of Missouri. Images from the 1920's include a German club photo from 1922 and two undated photos of Southwest Texas State Teacher College faculty. Identified staff members include: Alfred H. Nolle, E. O. Wiley, W. R. Boucher, Gates Thomas, A. C. Hurkholder, Mary C. Brogdon, and Georgia Lazenby. Photographs of Lyndon B. Jonson signing the Higher Education Act of 1965 are also included. A 1970 photograph of Dr. Nolle also includes fellow faculty member Robert Tampke and an individual identified as Harold C. Simon.
  - Photographs, before 1919-1970, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)